<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 07:45:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Vonnegut on being addicted to oil</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/kurt-vonnegut-on-being-addicted-to-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 07:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/kurt-vonnegut-on-being-addicted-to-oil/</guid>
      <description>From an interview in 2006 (video below):
I have a message for future generations. That is please accept our apologies.. we were roaring drunk on petroleum. Everything that distinguishes our era from the dark ages is what we&#39;ve been able to do with petroleum … and that is going to end very soon. I think in the next few years we&#39;re going to see the price of fossil fuels go through the roof, and there will be no substitutes for gasoline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the road of yellow brick</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/follow-the-road-of-yellow-brick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 23:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/follow-the-road-of-yellow-brick/</guid>
      <description>In L. Frank Baum&amp;rsquo;s The Wonderful Wizard of Oz, the road along which Dorothy walks is never referred to as the &amp;lsquo;yellow brick road&amp;rsquo;. Instead, it is known variously as:
 the road to the City of Emeralds [that] is paved with yellow brick
 the one paved with yellow bricks
 the hard, yellow road-bed
 the road of yellow brick
 the path of yellow brick
 the yellow bricks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Auster</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/paul-auster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2001 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/paul-auster/</guid>
      <description>Being a fan of the work of Paul Auster [author of The New York Trilogy, Leviathan etc.], I was chuffed to discover that he has directed a film called &amp;lsquo;Lulu On The Bridge&amp;rsquo;. I waited patiently for the film to appear somewhere [either on the cinema screens or &amp;lsquo;straight to video&amp;rsquo;] only to discover that no-one was willing to distribute it [at least in the UK anyway]. This was probably because either a) It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the mass appeal of mainstream pap or b) It was generally a bad film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From &#39;The Iron Man&#39; by Ted Hughes</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/from-the-iron-man-by-ted-hughes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2000 10:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/from-the-iron-man-by-ted-hughes/</guid>
      <description>One day there came strange news. Everybody was talking about it. Round eyes, busy mouths, frightened voices - everybody was talking about it.
One of the stars of the night sky had begun to change. This star had always been a very tiny star, of no importance at all. It had shone up there for billions and trillions and sillions of years in the Constellation of Orion, that great shape of the giant hunter that strides across space on autumn and winter nights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>