<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 12:15:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Typekit to work with Chromium and Namoroka</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/getting-typekit-to-work-with-chromium-and-namoroka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 12:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/getting-typekit-to-work-with-chromium-and-namoroka/</guid>
      <description>Typekit really need to improve the way they do their user-agent detection. At the moment, it seems that if the user-agent-string doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain either &amp;lsquo;Firefox&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Safari&amp;rsquo;, then Typekit won&amp;rsquo;t work, even when the rendering engine is capable of rendering the fonts.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t an issue for many. But it is if you&amp;rsquo;re using a development build of a browser, or you&amp;rsquo;re using a Linux distribution with a modified version of Firefox that, due to licensing restrictions, can&amp;rsquo;t use the Firefox branding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting gnome-shell as the default window manager</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/setting-gnome-shell-as-the-default-window-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 08:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/setting-gnome-shell-as-the-default-window-manager/</guid>
      <description>Gnome Shell will be the new window manager in Gnome 3, but it can be used in the current version of Gnome by installing the gnome-shell package, and running &amp;lsquo;gnome-shell &amp;ndash;replace&amp;rsquo; in a terminal.
To have Gnome Shell as the default window manager, setting the WINDOW_MANAGER environment variable won&amp;rsquo;t work in Gnome 2.28. Instead you need to install &amp;lsquo;gconf-editor&amp;rsquo; using your package manager, then go to:
/desktop/gnome/session/required_components
and set the &amp;lsquo;windowmanager&amp;rsquo; key to &amp;lsquo;gnome-shell&amp;rsquo; instead of &amp;lsquo;metacity&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nautilus Goes Spatial</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2004/03/nautilus-goes-spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2004 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2004/03/nautilus-goes-spatial/</guid>
      <description>This preview of GNOME 2.6 discusses an interesting development in its file manager, Nautilus.
Like the OS X Finder and Windows’ file manager, Nautilus currently has a browser-like user interface, meaning you use backward and forward buttons to navigate through the hierarchy of folders. In the new version, Nautilus has a spatial finder mode, making it much more like the user interface found on the original Macintosh operating system. Rather than using one window to browse files, multiple windows are used, each representing a single folder.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>