<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TV on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/tv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TV on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 09:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/tv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Doctor Who</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 09:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</guid>
      <description>I quite enjoyed Brian Cox&amp;rsquo;s Royal Institution lecture on the science of Doctor Who. The problem for me though is that Doctor Who is as far from being Science Fiction as the Harry Potter series, which is a shame as it was originally conceived as an educational programme that used time travel to explore scientific ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need another Cosmos</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/we-need-another-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 16:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/we-need-another-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>Today The Times ran a piece by Sarah Vine (wife of education secretary Michael Gove) criticising the BBC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Wonders of the Universe&amp;rsquo; and its apparently egocentric presenter Brian Cox.
To be fair to Cox it’s probably not his fault that the show is put together in such an over-the-top way. Not even Narcissus himself would have had the brass neck to stipulate this kind of treatment in his contract: long, lingering shots of the handsome professor silhouetted against a night sky, or languid close-ups of him gazing manfully into the middle distance, flashing his white teeth in a carefree yet attractively wistful smile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How MasterChef is prepared</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/how-masterchef-is-prepared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 20:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/how-masterchef-is-prepared/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s how it goes …
John and Greg are the only physical members of the production crew. The entire programme is conceived, produced and edited by some kind of monstrous autonomous machine that kidnaps members of the public (some of which it refers to as celebrities) and puts them, bewildered, into a large kitchen.
It then threatens them with something off-screen and unspeakable unless they cook food while they blather on about how much this competition means to them, how disappointed they&amp;rsquo;ll be if they lose, and how much they enjoy cooking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter from Walt Kraemer</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2003/09/a-letter-from-walt-kraemer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2003 08:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2003/09/a-letter-from-walt-kraemer/</guid>
      <description>Following up my response to yesterdays comment in the Pinball Song thread, Walt Kraemer has been kind enough to email me with some information about the song. So here it is, definitive and from the person who composed and produced it, everything you ever wanted to know about the Sesame Street Pinball Number Count.
 As composer and producer of Sesame Street’s Pinball Music I was flattered to find interest in something I created over a quarter of a century ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>