<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 10:51:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is cycling getting more or less dangerous?</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/is-cycling-getting-more-or-less-dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/is-cycling-getting-more-or-less-dangerous/</guid>
      <description>Lots of dodgy statistics and skirting round of issues in this BBC Magazine piece. The &amp;lsquo;Safety in numbers in the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; argument is bogus; the reason they have such numbers is because of the level of investment in cycling infrastructure there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How short-term thinking about road safety has failed to make liveable towns and cities</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/07/how-short-term-thinking-about-road-safety-has-failed-to-make-liveable-towns-and-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 08:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/07/how-short-term-thinking-about-road-safety-has-failed-to-make-liveable-towns-and-cities/</guid>
      <description>We had a teacher at school who used to give lectures on road safety. They were gruesome first-hand accounts designed to scare us into being attentive around roads. No-one questioned why a P.E. teacher in his Ron Hills always seemed to be the one on the scene with a shovel and a body bag. It also didn&amp;rsquo;t occur to anyone to ask why the roads were dangerous places to be in the first place, especially ones nearby to the school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The only kit you need is a bike</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/02/the-only-kit-you-need-is-a-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 19:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/02/the-only-kit-you-need-is-a-bike/</guid>
      <description>For the first two days of The Times Cities fit for cycling campaign, the reaction amongst cycling campaigners was unanimously positive. For the first time, cycle safety was being addressed in a way that didn&amp;rsquo;t blame the victims of cycling accidents, and furthermore, it was being addressed in a mainstream arena.
For too long, the emphasis has been placed on the cyclist to protect themselves in a dangerous environment, instead of looking at why our cities are dangerous places to cycle in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gateshead, Tesco</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/01/gateshead-tesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 15:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/01/gateshead-tesco/</guid>
      <description>In Gateshead town centre, huge steel structures are being bolted together like giant Meccano. Their sterile frames loom over and encroach the streets below in a way that demonstrates their designer&amp;rsquo;s lack of regard for the people who will be using the spaces around them.
This is the new Trinity Square, built on the site of Trinity Shopping Centre and its infamous car park designed by the late Rodney Gordon of Owen Luder Partnership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using your energy, not battery power, to light your bicycle</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/12/using-your-energy-not-battery-power-to-light-your-bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 08:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/12/using-your-energy-not-battery-power-to-light-your-bicycle/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I took a front wheel to a local bike shop to get a replacement spoke fitted. I handed it over to the sales assistant and the first thing he did was look at the hub and turn the spindle. &amp;ldquo;That hub&amp;rsquo;s absolutely buggered mate&amp;rdquo; he quickly concluded, referring to the apparent stiffness as it turned. He didn&amp;rsquo;t recognise that the hub was a dynamo, and the friction is there to generate electrical power as the wheel turns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Vonnegut on being addicted to oil</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/kurt-vonnegut-on-being-addicted-to-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 07:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/kurt-vonnegut-on-being-addicted-to-oil/</guid>
      <description>From an interview in 2006 (video below):
I have a message for future generations. That is please accept our apologies.. we were roaring drunk on petroleum. Everything that distinguishes our era from the dark ages is what we&#39;ve been able to do with petroleum … and that is going to end very soon. I think in the next few years we&#39;re going to see the price of fossil fuels go through the roof, and there will be no substitutes for gasoline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodland</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/02/woodland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 08:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/02/woodland/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An open letter to Newcastle City Council about the &#39;Ghost Street&#39; road safety campaign</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/02/an-open-letter-to-newcastle-city-council-about-the-ghost-street-road-safety-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 16:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/02/an-open-letter-to-newcastle-city-council-about-the-ghost-street-road-safety-campaign/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing with regard to your Ghost Street road safety campaign website, specifically the pages about pedestrians and cycling.
My question is how are we supposed to encourage more people to cycle or walk if campaigns like this scare them away from it? A safer environment for cyclists and pedestrians is one in which fewer people commute by car, and more people choose to cycle or walk instead. The problem is that people choose not to cycle or walk BECAUSE of the dangers presented by the number of cars on the road and lack of adequate infrastructure (especially for cyclists who often have to share the road with motorists).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID tags for cycles</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/rfid-tags-for-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 17:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/rfid-tags-for-cycles/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Northumbria Police had a stand at Newcastle Central Station giving away free RFID tags for your bike. The idea is that you register with the Immobitag website and enter the ID number printed on the tag. You then push the tag down the seat tube where it can&amp;rsquo;t be removed, at least not easily.
Then, if the bike is stolen and recovered by the police, they scan the bike for the tag and contact you to reunite you with your beloved machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering electronic devices while cycling</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/05/powering-electronic-devices-while-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/05/powering-electronic-devices-while-cycling/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought a Busch &amp;amp; Muller E-Werk hub dynamo powered supply unit to power and charge up devices while I&amp;rsquo;m cycling (I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually built the bike I&amp;rsquo;m going to attach it to yet, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different story!).

It&amp;rsquo;s a small device that plugs into a dynamo hub (in my case a Schmidt SON) and converts the AC output to DC at adjustable voltages. It comes with a large number of cables, including a variety of standard USB plugs and DC charger plugs that allow you to power your phone or charge up a dSLR battery while on the move.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>