<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 14:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone UK Stats</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/12/iphone-uk-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/12/iphone-uk-stats/</guid>
      <description>It will be interesting to see some figures for iPhone sales in the first few months of their release in the UK. I spend two and a half hours a day commuting, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen one iPhone in use. iPod Touch sales will be strong in the run up to Yule, but the startling gap between the quality of the iPhone UI that of its competitors doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem enough to lure us Brits away from our free phones and and choice of reasonable contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anil Dash on the smugness of Apple</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/10/anil-dash-on-the-smugness-of-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/10/anil-dash-on-the-smugness-of-apple/</guid>
      <description>Anil Dash on the smugness of Apple
When browsing your network in Leopard, machines running windows appear as beige monitors showing the Blue Screen of Death. Anil Dash takes issue with this:
The disdain here isn&#39;t for the unfortunate unwashed who have to suffer through Windows because they&#39;re so clueless -- it&#39;s a snide shot at the other computers you own, or of your family&#39;s other machines around the house, or of the computers of the peers you work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My love hate relationship with Apple, Inc</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/09/my-love-hate-relationship-with-apple-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 21:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/09/my-love-hate-relationship-with-apple-inc/</guid>
      <description>When Apple starts peddling ring tones as something other than simply an mp3 that you can use to alert you of an incoming call, locking down iPods so that they only work with iTunes, and making horrendous UI decisions such as the new Dock, you know it&amp;rsquo;s time to look elsewhere for computing and gadgetry needs.
Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having an inner conflict between, on one hand, the years of happy memories of using Apple products, the quality of their product design and the ease of use of OS X, and on the other, their slipshod attidude to peoples&amp;rsquo; freedoms, the brushed metal effect, and their amazing short-sightedness as to not open the iPhone as a platform for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Winer on one month with iPhone</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/dave-winer-on-one-month-with-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/dave-winer-on-one-month-with-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Remember, in the 80s Apple was the first company to build networking into every machine, and later the first company to ship a wifi router. Hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s possible for Apple to open today&amp;rsquo;s iPhone, and reward the early adopters for betting on them, and get developers busy at fulfilling the opportunities it creates as a platform, not just a device.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the rumour mill: On Monday, Apple will announce a European 3G iPhone for Vodafone, T-Mobile and Carphone Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/06/from-the-rumour-mill-on-monday-apple-will-announce-a-european-3g-iphone-for-vodafone-t-mobile-and-carphone-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 20:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/06/from-the-rumour-mill-on-monday-apple-will-announce-a-european-3g-iphone-for-vodafone-t-mobile-and-carphone-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>A faster network and choice over carriers; this would be a much better deal than the US version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-touch is only innovative when Apple does it?</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/06/multi-touch-is-only-innovative-when-apple-does-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 14:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/06/multi-touch-is-only-innovative-when-apple-does-it/</guid>
      <description>What follows is a revised comment I recently made on Reddit:
It&#39;s strange that when [Jeff Han](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Han) demonstrated his Multi-touch technology in 2006, everyone said how pioneering it was, and now that Microsoft are releasing similar technology, called [Surface](http://www.microsoft.com/surface/), people seem to be ridiculing it as a &#39;big-ass table&#39;. To me this satirical ad smacks of hypocrisy by someone who - I suspect - would be first in the queue if Apple released something similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS X Spaces</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/08/os-x-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/08/os-x-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Today’s unveiling of OS X v10.5 included a demonstration of Apple’s new implementation of virtual desktops, known as ‘Spaces’.
About bloomin’ time Apple!
The more we subscribe to the ‘digital lifestyle’, the more we multitask – it’s common practice to have our email, a web browser, instant chat, photos, and music open at once – and I’ve always felt OS X provided a very cramped environment to do all this. Moreover, I never found Expose a particularly good method of navigating these windows, and I consider it another bit of not-very-useful eye-candy akin the Dock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yesterday Apple’s share price closed at $80.86</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/yesterday-apples-share-price-closed-at-80.86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2006 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/yesterday-apples-share-price-closed-at-80.86/</guid>
      <description>The 8086 was Intel’s first 16bit x86 processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>There are too many short sharp syllables in the name ‘MacBook’ for my liking. I suppose they had to think of another name for the top-end portables now that they longer use the PowerPC chip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Lightroom</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/into-the-lightroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2006 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2006/01/into-the-lightroom/</guid>
      <description>Last year, Apple launched Aperture, an image management tool aimed at professional photographers. Just as Apple had introduced Final Cut Pro DV editing software to compete with Adobe Premier, many expected Apple to launch an image manipulation application to give Photoshop a run for its money on OS X. So people were quick to assume that Aperture was Apple’s answer to Photoshop, leading to many negative reviews with Aperture apparently lacking many of the features of Photoshop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>