<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 22:55:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPad</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</guid>
      <description>When Apple introduced the iPhone, it was like Steve Jobs reached through a mysterious wormhole and pulled from within it an object from five years into the future; its design and user interface were like nothing seen before.
With the iPad, it&amp;rsquo;s like Jobs picked up a five year old magazine article about what Apple might have in store for the future, and based their new product on that. It&amp;rsquo;s even called iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing up the Apple Tablet</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/sizing-up-the-apple-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 20:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/sizing-up-the-apple-tablet/</guid>
      <description>I doubt the Apple Tablet will be much bigger than the iPhone hardware. In the past, tablet PCs running Windows have been large and expensive devices, which is not a good combination for a hand-held product.
My prediction is something bigger than an iPhone (and just as thin and sleek), but no bigger than a Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Display is The Computer</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2004/08/the-display-is-the-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2004 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2004/08/the-display-is-the-computer/</guid>
      <description>This particular statement in Apple’s marketing blurb for the new iMac may owe its catchiness to Sun Microsystems, but it’s important because I believe the iMac G5 is a true successor to both the original iMac released and the original Macintosh computer released 20 years ago.
The G4 ‘anglepoise’ iMac was a great design, however while it was an all-in-one machine, its form-factor seemed to be a concession to the fact that, at the time, it was impossible to put an LCD display, a G4 processor, associated heatsink and circuitry into the same casing without it looking ugly as hell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black and Blum</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/black-and-blum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2001 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/black-and-blum/</guid>
      <description>Innovative product design and great photography at black+blum. Site design by Presence Multimedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPP 2000</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/cpp-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2001 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/cpp-2000/</guid>
      <description>CPP | 2000 - a half-finished greyscale dhtml site by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebTV Emulator</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/webtv-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2001 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/webtv-emulator/</guid>
      <description>According to Corey Eisman [toegristle], you can download a WebTV emulator from
here. Thanks Corey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namesake</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/namesake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2001 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/namesake/</guid>
      <description>Another Matt Jones weblog [Creative Director of news.bbc.co.uk no less]. Although I think the BBC News site is excellent and I read it regularly, I have one quibble: why don&amp;rsquo;t any of the articles contain hypertext? I would have thought a public service organisation like the BBC would be the first to maintain web design standards that help make the Web what it is. Presumably, the reasoning is that people might click on a hyperlink to another site, not like what they see and think to themselves &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not paying my licence fee for this rubbish!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XBox Design</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/xbox-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2001 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/xbox-design/</guid>
      <description>After all the hype, the xbox looks like a disappointing piece of product design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nielsen is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/nielsen-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2001 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/nielsen-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>There is something fundamentally wrong with Jakob Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s argument in his latest alertbox and I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble pinning down what it is. I agree that mobile phones are poor devices for viewing online content and that their &amp;lsquo;form factor&amp;rsquo; does not lend itself to interfacing successfully to the Internet. But he goes on to suggest that the future of mobile voice communication is through hand-held devices - primarily for Internet use - which have an ear/microphone arrangement for phone calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bezier Tool</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/bezier-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2000 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/bezier-tool/</guid>
      <description>Teaching students how to use the Bezier tool in Illustrator is damned tricky. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that takes a while to master and when you do get good at it, it becomes second nature to do loads of fancy key presses that do different things. I made the mistake of teaching it in reverse; I showed them all these keyboard shortcuts before explaining the tool itself. It confused a few people, but I think they appreciated the fact that I was willing to assume they weren&amp;rsquo;t all halfwits and that they&amp;rsquo;d pick it up quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>