<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comment on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/comment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comment on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:08:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/comment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Johann Hari&#39;s Wikipedia editing history as David Rose</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</guid>
      <description>Not quite in the same league of journalistic malpractice as phone hacking is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johann Hari&#39;s Wikipedia editing history as David Rose</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</guid>
      <description>Not quite in the same league of journalistic malpractice as phone hacking is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We need another Cosmos</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/we-need-another-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 16:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/03/we-need-another-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>Today The Times ran a piece by Sarah Vine (wife of education secretary Michael Gove) criticising the BBC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Wonders of the Universe&amp;rsquo; and its apparently egocentric presenter Brian Cox.
To be fair to Cox it’s probably not his fault that the show is put together in such an over-the-top way. Not even Narcissus himself would have had the brass neck to stipulate this kind of treatment in his contract: long, lingering shots of the handsome professor silhouetted against a night sky, or languid close-ups of him gazing manfully into the middle distance, flashing his white teeth in a carefree yet attractively wistful smile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPad</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</guid>
      <description>When Apple introduced the iPhone, it was like Steve Jobs reached through a mysterious wormhole and pulled from within it an object from five years into the future; its design and user interface were like nothing seen before.
With the iPad, it&amp;rsquo;s like Jobs picked up a five year old magazine article about what Apple might have in store for the future, and based their new product on that. It&amp;rsquo;s even called iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fox Hunting Ban</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/fox-hunting-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2001 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/fox-hunting-ban/</guid>
      <description>It looks as though there will be a total ban on fox-hunting, and about time too. I did some documentary photography work at a pro-hunting rally once and I can safely say that the hunt supporters I met there were - stereotypically - a bunch of useless arrogant toffs. Hard luck ladies and gents, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid you&amp;rsquo;re not going to have the enjoyment of chasing a defenceless fox around fields with a large pack of ill-treated dogs, only to watch as they eventually rip their quarry to pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Crisis</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/train-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2000 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/train-crisis/</guid>
      <description>The so called &amp;lsquo;train crisis&amp;rsquo; in the UK is really not as bad as the media is making out. I travelled from Newcastle to Crewe [a 4 hour journey requiring 2 changes of train] without any problems at all. In fact, the trains were completely empty [in the run up to Christmas!?].
As a result of my slightly hectic lifestyle, travelling is the only opportunity I get to have a good think and develop some ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>