<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:32:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Secular Americans praise Bloomberg - 9/11 ceremony religion free</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</guid>
      <description>A reflection of the cultural diversity of the victims of 9&amp;frasl;11 and a reminder that America is a secular country. Meanwhile, most of the remembrance services in the UK were entirely Christian affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s predicted that by 2050, regular church attendance will be made by less than 100,000 people in the UK. Yet the stranglehold Christianity has on events concerning national mourning and remembrance remains strong. I often wonder why that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The misguided idea of scientific fundamentalism</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 06:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</guid>
      <description>What follows is an edited and abridged email I sent to a friend as part of a debate on the topic of &amp;lsquo;scientific fundamentalism&amp;rsquo; and the proposal that &amp;lsquo;science can&amp;rsquo;t explain everything&amp;rsquo;.
Science as a big stick As the opening sequences of 2001: A Space Odyssey reveal, humans have always applied our knowledge to build tools to kill for food, defend ourselves and dominate and populate other lands. Science isn&amp;rsquo;t a new and dangerous development in the history of the human race; we&amp;rsquo;ve always sought to acquire knowledge about the world in order to give ourselves a competitive advantage over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fry &amp; Hitchens vs. The Hard of Thinking</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/fry--hitchens-vs.-the-hard-of-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 15:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/fry--hitchens-vs.-the-hard-of-thinking/</guid>
      <description>At the recent Intelligence Squared debate in London, Christopher Hitchens and Stephen Fry spoke against the motion &amp;lsquo;The catholic church is a force for good in the world&amp;rsquo;, while Archbishop John Onaiyekan and Anne Widdencombe MP failed to put forward a convincing argument for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herding Cats</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/herding-cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 21:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/herding-cats/</guid>
      <description>In one day, the Atheist Campaign have raised nearly ten times more money than their original target of £5500. So cats can be herded after all?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Ark</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/jurassic-ark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/jurassic-ark/</guid>
      <description>Jurassic Ark by sculptor Stephen Geddes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity Atheists</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</guid>
      <description>The Celebrity Atheist List contains many people who have enriched our society with scientific ideas, writing and music; showing that thinking independently and rationally is the key to moving humanity forward. But then there is also Barry Manilow on the list. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity Atheists</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2001 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</guid>
      <description>The Celebrity Atheist List contains many people who have enriched our society with scientific ideas, writing and music; showing that thinking independently and rationally is the key to moving humanity forward. But then there is also Barry Manilow on the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</guid>
      <description>Watching Channel 4&amp;#8217;s Neanderthal makes you realise that we have changed very little over the last 35,000 years. Everything about us; our emotions, the way we think, the structure of our society, even the way we behave in virtual communities, has the imprint of the behaviour of our ancient ancestors. I can well believe that Cro Magnon (our own species) &amp;#8211; with their superior intelligence &amp;#8211; made their way north and eventually wiped out the savage but otherwise peaceful Neanderthal species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2000 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</guid>
      <description>Watching Channel 4&amp;rsquo;s Neanderthal makes you realise that we have changed very little over the last 35,000 years. Everything about us; our emotions, the way we think, the structure of our society, even the way we behave in virtual communities, has the imprint of the behaviour of our ancient ancestors. I can well believe that Cro Magnon (our own species) - with their superior intelligence - made their way north and eventually wiped out the savage but otherwise peaceful Neanderthal species.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>