<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Celestial mechanics and the new political landscape</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/07/celestial-mechanics-and-the-new-political-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/07/celestial-mechanics-and-the-new-political-landscape/</guid>
      <description>In 2013 Comet ISON, a frozen lump of dust and gas about 1 kilometre in diameter was falling towards the sun. Known as a &amp;lsquo;sungrazing&amp;rsquo; comet, ISON&amp;rsquo;s orbit meant that its 3 million year journey from the outer solar system would end in a perilous encounter with our Star, and no-one knew if it would survive.
On November 28 that year, the comet reached perihelion - its closest point to the Sun - and astronomers waited to see what came round the other side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bowie and the 90s Internet</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/01/bowie-and-the-90s-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/01/bowie-and-the-90s-internet/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen the Paxman interview with David Bowie from 1999, in which he talks about the &amp;ldquo;unimaginable potential&amp;rdquo; of the Internet for democratising the music industry.
I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have experienced the Web in its infancy, and the sense that it was the start of a major and positive development in global knowledge-sharing and communication; the important factor being that it was under the ownership of everyone and not a handful of megacorporations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013: The Year the BBC Looked Like a Bogus Signer</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2014/01/2013-the-year-the-bbc-looked-like-a-bogus-signer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 22:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2014/01/2013-the-year-the-bbc-looked-like-a-bogus-signer/</guid>
      <description>If the BBC was a neutral broadcaster working on behalf of the public that funds it ... we might have expected it to broadcast the [mass protest about hospital cuts and the sell-off of the NHS](http://www.express.co.uk/news/uk/433173/50-000-people-march-in-Manchester-against-NHS-cuts), brokered by a political party that hasn&#39;t won an election for 22 years. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are All Netizens Now</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/we-are-all-netizens-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 22:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/we-are-all-netizens-now/</guid>
      <description>The Net means personal power in a world of little or no personal power (other than those on the top - who are called powerful because of money, but not because of thoughts or ideas). The essence of the Net is Communication, of personal communication between individual people, and between individuals and those who in society who care (and do not care) to listen.
Micheal Hauben - What the Net Means to Me The quote above is taken from an article written 1994, a few years after the invention of the Web and about 14 years before the mass-participation in social media networking sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Doctor Who</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 09:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</guid>
      <description>I quite enjoyed Brian Cox&amp;rsquo;s Royal Institution lecture on the science of Doctor Who. The problem for me though is that Doctor Who is as far from being Science Fiction as the Harry Potter series, which is a shame as it was originally conceived as an educational programme that used time travel to explore scientific ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nikon follow the lead of Fuji with the retro styled DF</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/nikon-follow-the-lead-of-fuji-with-the-retro-styled-df/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/nikon-follow-the-lead-of-fuji-with-the-retro-styled-df/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a type of photographer who yearns for knurled metal dials, aperture rings on the lens, and a shutter release button with a thread for a cable release&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is cycling getting more or less dangerous?</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/is-cycling-getting-more-or-less-dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/is-cycling-getting-more-or-less-dangerous/</guid>
      <description>Lots of dodgy statistics and skirting round of issues in this BBC Magazine piece. The &amp;lsquo;Safety in numbers in the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; argument is bogus; the reason they have such numbers is because of the level of investment in cycling infrastructure there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greasemonkey script to remove promoted tweets from Twitter</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/greasemonkey-script-to-remove-promoted-tweets-from-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 15:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/greasemonkey-script-to-remove-promoted-tweets-from-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Now that Twitter has gone public we can expect many changes that will keep shareholders happy but annoy long-term users of the site. For me, the addition of embedded images in the timeline breaks something fundamental about Twitter, the idea of creativity through limitation; a tweet is now 140 characters and an image (or an advert). This Greasemonkey script gets rid of the adverts, at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How short-term thinking about road safety has failed to make liveable towns and cities</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/07/how-short-term-thinking-about-road-safety-has-failed-to-make-liveable-towns-and-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 08:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/07/how-short-term-thinking-about-road-safety-has-failed-to-make-liveable-towns-and-cities/</guid>
      <description>We had a teacher at school who used to give lectures on road safety. They were gruesome first-hand accounts designed to scare us into being attentive around roads. No-one questioned why a P.E. teacher in his Ron Hills always seemed to be the one on the scene with a shovel and a body bag. It also didn&amp;rsquo;t occur to anyone to ask why the roads were dangerous places to be in the first place, especially ones nearby to the school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia &gt; New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/12/wikipedia--new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/12/wikipedia--new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>Mine is to take ownership of what I publish online by hosting it myself (ie. publish more stuff to this blog). I think I say that every year though.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>