<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 09:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Doctor Who</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 09:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/the-science-of-doctor-who/</guid>
      <description>I quite enjoyed Brian Cox&amp;rsquo;s Royal Institution lecture on the science of Doctor Who. The problem for me though is that Doctor Who is as far from being Science Fiction as the Harry Potter series, which is a shame as it was originally conceived as an educational programme that used time travel to explore scientific ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Dynamics Petman</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/11/boston-dynamics-petman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 07:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/11/boston-dynamics-petman/</guid>
      <description>Human Beings&amp;rsquo; greatest technological leaps seem to always stem from military applications, and Boston Dynamics humanoid robot &amp;lsquo;Petman&amp;rsquo; is no different in that respect. I look forward to the day then technology like this is developed to make our lives better, not to make war. It makes Honda&amp;rsquo;s Asimo - a corporate marketing tool - look like Robbie the Robot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park: Feathered Edition</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/jurassic-park-feathered-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 16:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/jurassic-park-feathered-edition/</guid>
      <description>Given the progress in computer generated effects over the last 17 years, as well as our better understanding of dinosaur evolution, maybe Steven Spielberg should re-edit Jurassic Park with more feathers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what the Velociraptor probably looked like, based on recent fossil discoveries…
Velociraptor mongoliensis, drawn by Matt Martyniuk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn &amp; Enceladus</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/saturn-enceladus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 10:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/saturn-enceladus/</guid>
      <description>Credit: NASA/JPL/Space Science Institute</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Athelete Prototype Mars Rover</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/nasa-athelete-prototype-mars-rover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 09:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/nasa-athelete-prototype-mars-rover/</guid>
      <description>This footage of NASA&amp;rsquo;s prototype Mars rover looks like something from a Ray Harryhausen film.
**Update: **I originally posted this on a computer without sound and was unaware of the annoying music. Apologies for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The misguided idea of scientific fundamentalism</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 06:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</guid>
      <description>What follows is an edited and abridged email I sent to a friend as part of a debate on the topic of &amp;lsquo;scientific fundamentalism&amp;rsquo; and the proposal that &amp;lsquo;science can&amp;rsquo;t explain everything&amp;rsquo;.
Science as a big stick As the opening sequences of 2001: A Space Odyssey reveal, humans have always applied our knowledge to build tools to kill for food, defend ourselves and dominate and populate other lands. Science isn&amp;rsquo;t a new and dangerous development in the history of the human race; we&amp;rsquo;ve always sought to acquire knowledge about the world in order to give ourselves a competitive advantage over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube - The Hubble Ultra Deep Field in 3D</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/youtube-the-hubble-ultra-deep-field-in-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 16:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/youtube-the-hubble-ultra-deep-field-in-3d/</guid>
      <description>YouTube - The Hubble Ultra Deep Field in 3D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1 Telescope Control Room</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/mark-1-telescope-control-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 12:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/mark-1-telescope-control-room/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1 Telescope Control Room, Jodrell Bank, Cheshire. Circa 1957.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Telescope</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/the-forgotten-telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 14:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/the-forgotten-telescope/</guid>
      <description>When students at South Tyneside Marine and Technical College learned about navigation at sea, they studied astronomy using the College&amp;rsquo;s planetarium and observatory. Now that navigation is done using the Global Positioning System, these facilities have become sadly unused. The college, now a place for general further education, is being redeveloped, which will see the observatory demolished and the telescope relocated to Stockton-on-Tees.
Last night, a few of us were lucky to get access to the scope and spend a couple of hours observing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add Comet Lulin to Stellarium</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/how-to-add-comet-lulin-to-stellarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 23:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/how-to-add-comet-lulin-to-stellarium/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the Northern Hemisphere, the best time to see Comet Lulin will be when it passes Saturn and heads towards Regulus in the constellation of Leo from the 23rd of February onwards. It should be visible to the naked eye if you have clear skies and should look pretty good through binoculars.
A good way to track its progress - and find out how to spot it - is to use Stellarium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>