<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:32:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Secular Americans praise Bloomberg - 9/11 ceremony religion free</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</guid>
      <description>A reflection of the cultural diversity of the victims of 9&amp;frasl;11 and a reminder that America is a secular country. Meanwhile, most of the remembrance services in the UK were entirely Christian affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s predicted that by 2050, regular church attendance will be made by less than 100,000 people in the UK. Yet the stranglehold Christianity has on events concerning national mourning and remembrance remains strong. I often wonder why that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The misguided idea of scientific fundamentalism</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 06:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-misguided-idea-of-scientific-fundamentalism/</guid>
      <description>What follows is an edited and abridged email I sent to a friend as part of a debate on the topic of &amp;lsquo;scientific fundamentalism&amp;rsquo; and the proposal that &amp;lsquo;science can&amp;rsquo;t explain everything&amp;rsquo;.
Science as a big stick As the opening sequences of 2001: A Space Odyssey reveal, humans have always applied our knowledge to build tools to kill for food, defend ourselves and dominate and populate other lands. Science isn&amp;rsquo;t a new and dangerous development in the history of the human race; we&amp;rsquo;ve always sought to acquire knowledge about the world in order to give ourselves a competitive advantage over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Up in the Universe</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/04/growing-up-in-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 13:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/04/growing-up-in-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>In 1991, Richard Dawkins presented the Royal Institution Christmas lectures for Children, and to help illustrate our tendency to think we are superior to the rest of the species on the planet, he invited a member of the audience to read an excerpt from Hitch-hiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy:
Growing up in the Universe
The lecture series, titled &amp;lsquo;Growing up the Universe&amp;rsquo; has recently been released on DVD. I remember it when it was first broadcast on the BBC, and as a 15 year-old who&amp;rsquo;d had a vaguely Christian education and thus had many unanswered questions about our origins, it was a wonderfully inspiring and educational piece of television.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>