<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/categories/freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:02:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/categories/freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The freedom to offend in 140 characters</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-freedom-to-offend-in-140-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/11/the-freedom-to-offend-in-140-characters/</guid>
      <description>We cannot have a web on which a 140 character utterance of criticism against someone else causes a torrent of abuse against the offender and a front-page BBC article about the offendee&amp;rsquo;s intention to quit because of it.
Yesterday, Twitter user Brumplum criticised Stephen Fry by calling his tweets boring, and Stephen Fry reacted by threatening to quit Twitter. We&amp;rsquo;ll look back on this and see how silly it all is, and in future BBC editors with publish more important news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Fear of Socialised Medicine</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/the-american-fear-of-socialised-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 16:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/the-american-fear-of-socialised-medicine/</guid>
      <description>In 1960, the American Medical Association ran a campaign against the Democrats&amp;rsquo; plans for free health care for the elderly. Calling it &amp;lsquo;Operation Coffee Cup&amp;rsquo;, they hired Ronald Reagan to record an LP entitled &amp;lsquo;Ronald Reagan speaks out against SOCIALIZED MEDICINE&amp;rsquo;. In it, he warns that socialised medicine is &amp;ldquo;a foot in the door&amp;rdquo; for further government intervention, and that &amp;ldquo;pretty soon your son won&amp;rsquo;t decide when he&amp;rsquo;s in school, where he will go or what he will do for a living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a photographer, not a terrorist.</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/im-a-photographer-not-a-terrorist./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 20:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/im-a-photographer-not-a-terrorist./</guid>
      <description>Photography is under attack. Across the country it that seems anyone with a camera is being targeted as a potential terrorist, whether amateur or professional, whether landscape, architectural or street photographer. Not only is it corrosive of press freedom but creation of the collective visual history of our country is extinguished by anti-terrorist legislation designed to protect the heritage it prevents us recording. This campaign is for everyone who values visual imagery, not only photographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Nation under CCTV</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/one-nation-under-cctv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 11:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/one-nation-under-cctv/</guid>
      <description>Photo of Banky artwork by Dr Case (cc). Flickr.
Watching the watchers: Inside Westminster&amp;rsquo;s CCTV control centre</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Fingers?</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/01/how-many-fingers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/01/how-many-fingers/</guid>
      <description>According to Rudolph W. Guiliani:
Freedom is about authority. War is peace.
Ignorance is strength.
...anarchy would result if everyone were allowed to behave exactly as he wanted and cited Oliver Wendell Holmes&#39;s adage that freedom of expression does not include shouting &#39;Fire!&#39; in a crowded theater. That&amp;rsquo;s just a lack of common sense.
The New York Times | Some Free Speech on Mayor&amp;rsquo;s Words</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo 1973: Free Your Phone</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/neo-1973-free-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/neo-1973-free-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>In 1973, standing on a pavement in Manhattan, Marty Cooper made the first mobile phone call. Inspired by the communications devices used in Star Trek, Cooper developed a device that allowed phone calls to be made to anywhere in the world without being connected to the recipient by wires.
Today, OpenMoko and FIC have launched the first phone to run on a Free and Open Source Software platform, and as a tribute to that first mobile call, they&amp;rsquo;ve named it the Neo 1973.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-Infingement</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/meta-infingement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2001 13:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/meta-infingement/</guid>
      <description>The case of the meta-infringement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>