<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Celestial mechanics and the new political landscape</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/07/celestial-mechanics-and-the-new-political-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/07/celestial-mechanics-and-the-new-political-landscape/</guid>
      <description>In 2013 Comet ISON, a frozen lump of dust and gas about 1 kilometre in diameter was falling towards the sun. Known as a &amp;lsquo;sungrazing&amp;rsquo; comet, ISON&amp;rsquo;s orbit meant that its 3 million year journey from the outer solar system would end in a perilous encounter with our Star, and no-one knew if it would survive.
On November 28 that year, the comet reached perihelion - its closest point to the Sun - and astronomers waited to see what came round the other side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bowie and the 90s Internet</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/01/bowie-and-the-90s-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2016/01/bowie-and-the-90s-internet/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen the Paxman interview with David Bowie from 1999, in which he talks about the &amp;ldquo;unimaginable potential&amp;rdquo; of the Internet for democratising the music industry.
I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have experienced the Web in its infancy, and the sense that it was the start of a major and positive development in global knowledge-sharing and communication; the important factor being that it was under the ownership of everyone and not a handful of megacorporations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are All Netizens Now</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/we-are-all-netizens-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 22:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2013/11/we-are-all-netizens-now/</guid>
      <description>The Net means personal power in a world of little or no personal power (other than those on the top - who are called powerful because of money, but not because of thoughts or ideas). The essence of the Net is Communication, of personal communication between individual people, and between individuals and those who in society who care (and do not care) to listen.
Micheal Hauben - What the Net Means to Me The quote above is taken from an article written 1994, a few years after the invention of the Web and about 14 years before the mass-participation in social media networking sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johann Hari&#39;s Wikipedia editing history as David Rose</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</guid>
      <description>Not quite in the same league of journalistic malpractice as phone hacking is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johann Hari&#39;s Wikipedia editing history as David Rose</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 09:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/johann-haris-wikipedia-editing-history-as-david-rose/</guid>
      <description>Not quite in the same league of journalistic malpractice as phone hacking is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secular Americans praise Bloomberg - 9/11 ceremony religion free</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/09/secular-americans-praise-bloomberg---9/11-ceremony-religion-free/</guid>
      <description>A reflection of the cultural diversity of the victims of 9&amp;frasl;11 and a reminder that America is a secular country. Meanwhile, most of the remembrance services in the UK were entirely Christian affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s predicted that by 2050, regular church attendance will be made by less than 100,000 people in the UK. Yet the stranglehold Christianity has on events concerning national mourning and remembrance remains strong. I often wonder why that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Fear of Socialised Medicine</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/the-american-fear-of-socialised-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 16:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/the-american-fear-of-socialised-medicine/</guid>
      <description>In 1960, the American Medical Association ran a campaign against the Democrats&amp;rsquo; plans for free health care for the elderly. Calling it &amp;lsquo;Operation Coffee Cup&amp;rsquo;, they hired Ronald Reagan to record an LP entitled &amp;lsquo;Ronald Reagan speaks out against SOCIALIZED MEDICINE&amp;rsquo;. In it, he warns that socialised medicine is &amp;ldquo;a foot in the door&amp;rdquo; for further government intervention, and that &amp;ldquo;pretty soon your son won&amp;rsquo;t decide when he&amp;rsquo;s in school, where he will go or what he will do for a living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a photographer, not a terrorist.</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/im-a-photographer-not-a-terrorist./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 20:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/08/im-a-photographer-not-a-terrorist./</guid>
      <description>Photography is under attack. Across the country it that seems anyone with a camera is being targeted as a potential terrorist, whether amateur or professional, whether landscape, architectural or street photographer. Not only is it corrosive of press freedom but creation of the collective visual history of our country is extinguished by anti-terrorist legislation designed to protect the heritage it prevents us recording. This campaign is for everyone who values visual imagery, not only photographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Nation under CCTV</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/one-nation-under-cctv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 11:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/one-nation-under-cctv/</guid>
      <description>Photo of Banky artwork by Dr Case (cc). Flickr.
Watching the watchers: Inside Westminster&amp;rsquo;s CCTV control centre</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UK needs the independent web</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/the-uk-needs-the-independent-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 22:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/the-uk-needs-the-independent-web/</guid>
      <description>The bloggers were a major force for political change in the United States, and in the run up to the US election, the presidential candidates were listening to them. They helped shape public opinion, an army of geeks facilitated a faultless online campaign and now Obama is revolutionising how the web is used to communicate to the American people.
Why do we seem so far away from such a grassroots effort in the UK?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>