<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 15:59:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gateshead, Tesco</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/01/gateshead-tesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 15:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2012/01/gateshead-tesco/</guid>
      <description>In Gateshead town centre, huge steel structures are being bolted together like giant Meccano. Their sterile frames loom over and encroach the streets below in a way that demonstrates their designer&amp;rsquo;s lack of regard for the people who will be using the spaces around them.
This is the new Trinity Square, built on the site of Trinity Shopping Centre and its infamous car park designed by the late Rodney Gordon of Owen Luder Partnership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urbis, Manchester</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/urbis-manchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 23:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/03/urbis-manchester/</guid>
      <description>Urbis, Manchester</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Telescope</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/the-forgotten-telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 14:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/02/the-forgotten-telescope/</guid>
      <description>When students at South Tyneside Marine and Technical College learned about navigation at sea, they studied astronomy using the College&amp;rsquo;s planetarium and observatory. Now that navigation is done using the Global Positioning System, these facilities have become sadly unused. The college, now a place for general further education, is being redeveloped, which will see the observatory demolished and the telescope relocated to Stockton-on-Tees.
Last night, a few of us were lucky to get access to the scope and spend a couple of hours observing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Spaces</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/soft-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2001 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/soft-spaces/</guid>
      <description>living in, around, and with soft spaces - v-2.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art of Work</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/art-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2001 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/art-of-work/</guid>
      <description>art-of-work.com is an online recruitment agency recognising that &amp;ldquo;artists are a valuable human resource in the new work paradigms of open office architecture and new management techniques&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grim North</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/grim-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2000 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/grim-north/</guid>
      <description>Up here in the grim north, it’s fair to say that us creative types are starved of things to inspire and lift us. So what have we got? Well, there’s the Angel of North and the new Millennium Bridge, but we’re pretty over saturated with large and interesting metal objects dominating the skyline as it is. What’s missing is any kind of new media art/design community, a sense of things happening and moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millennium Bridge</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/millennium-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2000 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/millennium-bridge/</guid>
      <description>Some images of the bridge being put into place. Told you that crane is damned big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bridge</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/new-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2000 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/new-bridge/</guid>
      <description>Just used my lunch hour to check out the &amp;lsquo;Millennium Bridge&amp;rsquo; currently being installed on the Tyne. They&amp;rsquo;re floating it up river on a super-massive crane, apparently the largest one of its type in the world. Quite an impressive sight I can tell you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Screensavers</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/cool-screensavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2000 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/11/cool-screensavers/</guid>
      <description>Download some cool screensavers at the ICA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>