<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 07:18:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Dynamics Petman</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/11/boston-dynamics-petman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 07:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/11/boston-dynamics-petman/</guid>
      <description>Human Beings&amp;rsquo; greatest technological leaps seem to always stem from military applications, and Boston Dynamics humanoid robot &amp;lsquo;Petman&amp;rsquo; is no different in that respect. I look forward to the day then technology like this is developed to make our lives better, not to make war. It makes Honda&amp;rsquo;s Asimo - a corporate marketing tool - look like Robbie the Robot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iCloud</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/06/apple-icloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 11:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2011/06/apple-icloud/</guid>
      <description>Apple products once had names like Macintosh and Newton. While the iMac revolutionised PC design, it&amp;rsquo;s the anticedant of dreary names like &amp;lsquo;iCloud&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Paper and the Betamax Tape</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/11/electronic-paper-and-the-betamax-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 08:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/11/electronic-paper-and-the-betamax-tape/</guid>
      <description>As technology companies compete with each other, drive manufacturing costs down and put their marketing machines on full power, it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how they can steer us away from technologies that are clearly better for specific tasks than others.
When Apple launched the iPad, it made a big deal about the new iBook store and the iPad&amp;rsquo;s use as an electronic reading device. Here&amp;rsquo;s the marketing blurb on Apple&amp;rsquo;s site&amp;hellip;
Reading on iPad is just like reading a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arthur C. Clarke Predicts the Future</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/09/arthur-c.-clarke-predicts-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 09:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/09/arthur-c.-clarke-predicts-the-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Athelete Prototype Mars Rover</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/nasa-athelete-prototype-mars-rover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 09:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/08/nasa-athelete-prototype-mars-rover/</guid>
      <description>This footage of NASA&amp;rsquo;s prototype Mars rover looks like something from a Ray Harryhausen film.
**Update: **I originally posted this on a computer without sound and was unaware of the annoying music. Apologies for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering electronic devices while cycling</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/05/powering-electronic-devices-while-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/05/powering-electronic-devices-while-cycling/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought a Busch &amp;amp; Muller E-Werk hub dynamo powered supply unit to power and charge up devices while I&amp;rsquo;m cycling (I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually built the bike I&amp;rsquo;m going to attach it to yet, but that&amp;rsquo;s a different story!).

It&amp;rsquo;s a small device that plugs into a dynamo hub (in my case a Schmidt SON) and converts the AC output to DC at adjustable voltages. It comes with a large number of cables, including a variety of standard USB plugs and DC charger plugs that allow you to power your phone or charge up a dSLR battery while on the move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPad</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2010/01/apple-ipad/</guid>
      <description>When Apple introduced the iPhone, it was like Steve Jobs reached through a mysterious wormhole and pulled from within it an object from five years into the future; its design and user interface were like nothing seen before.
With the iPad, it&amp;rsquo;s like Jobs picked up a five year old magazine article about what Apple might have in store for the future, and based their new product on that. It&amp;rsquo;s even called iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>90 Orbits</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/02/90-orbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/02/90-orbits/</guid>
      <description>Arthur C. Clarke reflects on 90 orbits around the Sun. I was quite moved by this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lone iPhone</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/02/lone-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/02/lone-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Two months after the first sighting, I thought I saw another iPhone on my daily commute. Turned out it was the same person using the same iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo 1973: Free Your Phone</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/neo-1973-free-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/07/neo-1973-free-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>In 1973, standing on a pavement in Manhattan, Marty Cooper made the first mobile phone call. Inspired by the communications devices used in Star Trek, Cooper developed a device that allowed phone calls to be made to anywhere in the world without being connected to the recipient by wires.
Today, OpenMoko and FIC have launched the first phone to run on a Free and Open Source Software platform, and as a tribute to that first mobile call, they&amp;rsquo;ve named it the Neo 1973.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>