<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 14:43:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freedom of the Library</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/07/the-freedom-of-the-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 14:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2009/07/the-freedom-of-the-library/</guid>
      <description>Newcastle City Library isn&amp;rsquo;t really just a library; it is a cultural venue as significant to the city than the flagship venues of The Sage and BALTIC. There&amp;rsquo;s an openness to the place, from the glass exterior, to the open plan interior, and to the fact it&amp;rsquo;s completely self-service.
Initially, the library was accused of an &amp;lsquo;appalling lack of security&amp;rsquo; for not requiring identification when registering for the service. I congratulate the Library on showing a level of trust which otherwise seems to be rare in our civic spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preaching Reason</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/preaching-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 16:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2008/10/preaching-reason/</guid>
      <description>On a Saturday afternoon, Grey&amp;rsquo;s Monument in Newcastle usually hosts Christian evangelists from different groups using various methods to indoctrinate passers-by with their religion; from the hell-and-damnation-type shouting preachers to the well organised and massively funded Alpha Course, who cleverly use the &amp;lsquo;Big Question&amp;rsquo; type of rhetoric to encourage people to sign up for a ten week course on the Bible.
Today, handing out leaflets near a small table stacked with printed material, were two representatives from the North East Humanists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do schools kill creativity?</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/04/do-schools-kill-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2007 12:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2007/04/do-schools-kill-creativity/</guid>
      <description>I believe our only hope for the future it to adopt a new conception of human ecology, one in which we start we reconstitute our conception of the richness of human capacity. Our education system has mined our minds in the way that we have strip-mined the earth for a particular commodity, and for the future it won&#39;t service. We have to rethink the fundamental principles on which we&#39;re educating our children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2001 16:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to James, Timo and Rik for their comments and advice regarding my dilemma [as mentioned a few entries ago]. That&amp;rsquo;s appreciated, ta.
Just bought myself a motor to runaround in… who needs these new fangled economical cars anyway?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Web Design</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/teaching-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2001 13:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/02/teaching-web-design/</guid>
      <description>For a bit of extra cash, I have secured another contract to teach web design to a bunch of photography students during a series of evening classes.
The first session went well, I taught the basic concepts of Mark-Up, a brief history of the Web, the ‘browser wars’ and the importance of standards [I used the analogy of ISO photographic film speeds such 100 and 200 etc., – clever huh?] .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website in 12 Hours</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/website-in-12-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2001 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/website-in-12-hours/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got 12 hours to teach a group of photography students on how to get a website up and running. Bearing in mind that most of them know little about web design [or computers in general for that matter], I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to be pretty difficult in the time I&amp;rsquo;ve got. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to teach them how to create and maintain a weblog which would compliment an online folio of photography work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Students</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/rich-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2001 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/rich-students/</guid>
      <description>Today, one my students told me that her parents are about to buy her a Mac, but she&amp;rsquo;s not sure which one to get. She didn&amp;rsquo;t know about the G4 Powerbook until I told her about it, so guess what she is going to ask Mummy and Daddy for now? Makes you sick, no?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve Met Ive!</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/ive-met-ive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2000 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/ive-met-ive/</guid>
      <description>None other than Jonathan Ive [lead designer at Apple and the person responsible for the iMac and the Cube etc] was here in the office the other day. He was picking up an honourary degree from Northumbria Uni where he studied Industrial Design 10 years ago [the course I do a bit of teaching on]. He had an ‘entourage’ of university VIP types around him and I’m sure he really couldn’t be arsed with it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>