<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Matt Jones</title>
    <link>https://mattjon.es/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Matt Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattjon.es/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity Atheists</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/celebrity-atheists/</guid>
      <description>The Celebrity Atheist List contains many people who have enriched our society with scientific ideas, writing and music; showing that thinking independently and rationally is the key to moving humanity forward. But then there is also Barry Manilow on the list. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skye 2</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/skye-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2001/01/skye-2/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from spending New Year on the Island of Skye. Due to some tricky driving conditions and some poor navigating on my part, it took us a grueling 9 hours to get there, but it was [mostly] worth it. My only disappointment is that we didn&amp;#8217;t see enough of the island, we just didn&amp;#8217;t have enough time. Well actually, there was plenty of time, but we&amp;#8217;re such an unorganised bunch that by the time we&amp;#8217;d faffed around with breakfast, then sat around for a bit&amp;#8230; then finally managed to put our walking boots on, it seemed to go dark (about 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal</title>
      <link>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattjon.es/blog/2000/12/neanderthal/</guid>
      <description>Watching Channel 4&amp;#8217;s Neanderthal makes you realise that we have changed very little over the last 35,000 years. Everything about us; our emotions, the way we think, the structure of our society, even the way we behave in virtual communities, has the imprint of the behaviour of our ancient ancestors. I can well believe that Cro Magnon (our own species) &amp;#8211; with their superior intelligence &amp;#8211; made their way north and eventually wiped out the savage but otherwise peaceful Neanderthal species.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>